<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Obsidian]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><image><url>site-lib/media/favicon.png</url><title>Obsidian</title><link></link></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 19:00:26 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="site-lib/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 19:00:24 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator></dc:creator><item><title><![CDATA[Master's Thesis]]></title><description><![CDATA[IntroductionPairs trading is a portfolio construction technique that originated on Wall Street in the mid-1980's. The strategy was first developed by Nunzio Tartaglia and his research team at Morgan Stanley. In 1987, Morgan Stanley reportedly achieved profits of approximately $50 million through pairs trading; however, the strategy was later discontinued due to weaker performance in the following years. Nevertheless, pair trading has since remained a prominent and widely studied market-neutral strategy within both academic research and professional trading practice.The objective of pair to exploit relative price movements between two economically related assets. Its core principle lies in identifying pairs whose prices exhibit a consistent long-term co-movement and strategically profiting from short-term deviations from this equilibrium relationship. A defining feature of pair trading is its market-neutral nature, as it seeks to isolate and capitalize on relative mispricings between assets while remaining largely unaffected by overall market direction. Consequently, the focus of the investor shifts from predicting the absolute direction of the market to forecasting the relative performance between the pairs. Hence, the fundamental premise of a pairs trading strategy relies on the existence of a long-term equilibrium between two prices: While individual assets may experience significant price fluctuations, the relative price remains relatively stable. Pairs trading involves a three-step procedure: (1) selection of pairs, (2) threshold definition, (3) implementation and performance analysis. In step (1) two assets, or groups of assets, are identified. The challenge lies in identifying suitable pairs that exhibits a meaningful degree of co-movement. The objective of the pair is to generate a spread that produces an artificial stationary time series that replicates the behavior of a mean-reverting asset. Step (2) involves identifying the thresholds at which the pair's position is open and closed. Choosing optimal thresholds is crucial in implementing profitable strategies as they define entry and exit points, directly influencing trading decisions. The last stage involves the implementation of the strategy out-of-sample to assess the profit
characterization of the strategies. A comparative analysis between the pair trading strategy and
benchmarks such as the traditional buy-and-hold approach or the equally weighted portfolio can be
used to assess whether the additional effort and complexity of pair trading lead to superior returns.
This comparison clarifies the effectiveness and risk-adjusted returns of pair trading, providing insights
into its potential as an alternative investment strategy.The structure of the present dissertation is as follows. ]]></description><link>master&apos;s-thesis.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Master&apos;s Thesis.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 09:36:32 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>